Guide to the King-Lui Wu Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Project files, 1942-1991; Series I
  - Urban Housing Unit, proposed (including perspective views and drawings)
    - Drawings (Folder 29)
  - Villa K.K addition
    - Drawings (Folder 12)
  - Wang Laboratories (Proposed), 1958
    Job location: Redding, CT
    - Drawings (Folder 56)
  - Wang, Dr. and Mrs. An: Addition, 1958
    Job location: Lincoln
    - Drawings (Box 91, Folder 9c, Folder 24, Folder 53)
    - Photographs (Box 96, Box 98)
  - Webb, Mr. and Mrs. Dwight: Proposed addition to Residence
    Job location: Westport, CT
    - Drawings (Folder 51)
  - Wheaton College Art Center (Walter Gropius & Marcel Breuer, Second Prize, Cambridge, MA)
    - Drawings (Folder 75)
  - Wong, Dr. and Mrs. Andrew: Residence, 1964-1966
    - Drawings (Box 9, Box 91, Folder 52)
  - Wu, Bo-Jack: Addition, 1981
    Job location: Norwich, CT
    - Drawings (Box 91)
  - Wu, Mr. and Mrs. K.L.: Residence, 1977
    - Drawings (Folder 10, Folder 24)
  - Yali Middle School
    Job location: Changsha, China
    - Drawings (Folder 66, Folder 83, Folder 85)
  - Yali: Bird's Eye view
    - Drawings (Folder 67)
  - Yali: Proposed building, Yale in China
    - Drawings (Folder 76, Folder 79, Folder 85)
  - Yu, Mrs. Ling, 1968
    - Drawings (Box 91, Folder 12, Folder 41)
- Professional papers, 1954-2000, undated; Series II
  - Correspondence and communications
    - General professional, 1954-2000, undated (Box 100, Folder 1-15)
    - Yale University
      - General, 1963-1997, undated (Box 100, Folder 16-21)
      - Yale-China Association, 1980-1988 (Box 100, Folder 22)
      - Ezra-Stiles College fellow, 1967-1991 (Box 100, Folder 23)
      - Bulletin, 1965-1966 (Box 100, Folder 24)
      - Commencement, 1966 (Box 100, Folder 25)
      - News bureau, Undated (Box 100, Folder 26)
    - Yale School of Architecture
      - General, 1958-1996, undated (Box 101, Folder 1-8)
      - Presentations and lectures by others, 1966-1985 (Box 101, Folder 9)
      - Retrospecta, 1981-1991 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      - Bulletins of Yale University School of Art and Architecture, 1959-1978 (Box 101, Folder 11)
      - Commencement, 1966 (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - Eastern Kentucky Program, Undated (Box 101, Folder 13)
      - Faculty exhibition, 1991 (Box 101, Folder 14)
      - Art and Architecture building dedication, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 15)
      - History - notes, Undated (Box 101, Folder 16)
      - Mission statement, 1983 (Box 101, Folder 17)
      - Notable alumni, Undated (Box 101, Folder 18)
      - Administrative notes, 1983, undated (Box 101, Folder 19)
      - Retirement, 1988 (Box 101, Folder 20)
      - Thesis instructions and jury information, 1964-1987 (Box 101, Folder 21)
    - Invitations, 1961-1994, undated (Box 101, Folder 22)
  - Financial and legal documents
    - Invoices, furniture and miscellaneous, 1959-1985 (Box 101, Folder 23-24)
    - Office lease, 1960-1961 (Box 101, Folder 25)
    - Notes on furniture and roofing, 1976-1978 (Box 101, Folder 26)
  - Printed material
    - Newspapers, 1974-2001, undated (Box 101, Folder 27)
    - Magazines, pamphlets and catalogues, 1963-1982 (Box 101, Folder 28)
    - Articles on lighting, 1969-1981 (Box 101, Folder 29)
    - Articles on architecture and gardens, 1975-1996, undated (Box 101, Folder 30)
  - Professional documents
    - Resume
      - General, 1979-1997 (Box 101, Folder 31)
      - Computer files [1.4 megabytes]
    - Curriculum vitae, 1961-1980 (Box 101, Folder 32)
    - Business cards, 1970-1989, undated (Box 101, Folder 33)
    - Calendar, 1992 (Box 101, Folder 34)
  - Professional engagements and activities
    - Illuminated Engineering Society Joint Daylighting symposium, Beijing, China, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Joseph Albers Foundation, 1979-1984 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Mi Chou gallery exhibition, New York, NY, 1956 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Film project about King-Lui Wu, 1972-1977 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - College of St. Benedict, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Green Mountain College, 1995 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Hotchkiss School, 1989-1991 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - University of Cambridge, 1973-1974 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Graduate School of Design council, Undated (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Daylight and architecture, McGill University, 1980 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Chinese gardens: painting with nature, Toronto, 1990 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - Housing and daylight and architecture, Tong Ji University at Shanghai, 1982 (Box 102, Folder 12)
    - Daylight and architecture, MIT, 1977 (Box 102, Folder 13)
    - The future of Chinese architecture, MIT, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 14)
    - Daylight and architecture, Chicago, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 15)
    - Lectures in China, 1981-1983 (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - "A Search for Architecture," Southern Connecticut State College, 1969 (Box 103)
  - Research material and notes
    - Notes on architectural work, 1963-1992, undated (Box 102, Folder 17-21)
    - Hotels in China, 1981-1988 (Box 102, Folder 22)
    - Housing for China, 1981-1993 (Box 102, Folder 23-26)
    - Gardens, 1968-1994, undated (Box 102, Folder 27-28)
    - Architectural lighting, 1987, undated (Box 102, Folder 29)
    - Food and the Chinese concept of life, Undated (Box 102, Folder 30)
    - Favorite stories, Undated (Box 102, Folder 31)
    - Personal notebooks, 1992 (Box 102, Folder 32)
    - Book notes, Undated (Box 102, Folder 33)
    - Plans for Ezra Stiles and Branford colleges, Undated (Box 102, Folder 34)
    - Maps, 1965, undated (Box 102, Folder 35)
  - Travel
    - China, 1981 (Box 102, Folder 36)
    - Other, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 37)
  - Writings
    - Yale-China article, 1983-1984 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Garden-home of China book, 1978-1987, undated (Box 104, Folder 2-6)
    - Biographical sketch of Ssu-cheng Liang, 1981 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Yale teaching and lecture materials
    - A1 first-year studio, 1965-1971 (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - A1 studio, 1982-1984 (Box 104, Folder 9-10)
    - B1 studio, 1975-1976 (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - B2 studio, 1973, undated (Box 104, Folder 12-13)
    - B3 studio, 1980-1982 (Box 104, Folder 14-15)
    - B4 studio, 1977-1979 (Box 104, Folder 16-18)
    - B6 studio, 1972 (Box 104, Folder 19)
    - B8 studio, 1977 (Box 104, Folder 20)
    - B9 studio, 1977-1984 (Box 104, Folder 21-25)
    - B10 studio, 1981-1988 (Box 104, Folder 26-28)
    - B12 studio, 1970-1979 (Box 104, Folder 29-32)
    - First-year studio, 1979-1980 (Box 104, Folder 33)
    - Fourth-year design, 1956-1969 (Box 104, Folder 34)
    - GD134B urban graphics, 1972 (Box 104, Folder 35)
    - Second-year studio, 1970 (Box 104, Folder 36)
    - Thesis class, 1963-1967 (Box 104, Folder 37)
    - Third-year design, 1964-1967 (Box 104, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous housing studios, 1976-1985 (Box 104, Folder 39-42)
    - Celebrating the Rudolph years, YSOA, 1981 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Chinese poetry and the art of gardens, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Chinese culture and the art of gardens, 1986-1997 (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Daylight, 1974-1996, undated (Box 105, Folder 4-17)
    - Garden-home of China, 1983-1995, undated (Box 105, Folder 18-21)
    - Garden-home of China lectures, 1983, undated (Box 105, Folder 22-23)
    - Miscellaneous course and teaching materials, 1996 (Box 105, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous lectures, 1972-1991, undated (Box 105, Folder 25-27)
- Personal correspondence, 1960-1995, undated; Series III (Box 106, Folder 1-9)
- Computer files (Box 107, Reel 108)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.